# Moein Khajehnejad

☐ +61 (423) 591 018 • ☑ moein.khajehnejad@gmail.com • ② Personal Webpage in moein-khajehnejad • ۞ Moein-Khajehnejad

# Bio

I am a recent PhD graduate in Data Science with more than **8 years** of experience in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence research among prestigious teams in multiple of the world's **top 50 research institutes** in **6 different countries**. Passionate about theoretical computer science, I study populations and time series data using machine learning and game theory. I have made significant contributions to the state-of-the-art methods in analysis of collective behaviour and decision-making in multi-agent systems.

# **Education**

Monash University Melbourne

Ph.D., Department of Data Science and AI 2019 - 2023

**Sharif University of Technology** 

B.Sc., Computer Sciences & Electrical Engineering 2011 - 2016

**Working Experience** 

Cortical Labs pty ltd
Data Scientist - Part Time

Jan 2022 - Current

Melbourne

**Tehran** 

- Achievement: Developed deep RL algorithms and compared sample efficiency with live biological neurons.
- Duties: Building strong working relationships with international teams, Liaising with internal stakeholder, Communicating with non-technical audience, Working within cross-disciplinary teams.
- o Tools: PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, Scipy, Matplotlib, scikit-learn, holoviews, Pandas, Jupyter Lab, GitLab

## Max Planck Institute for Software Systems (MPI-SWS)

Saarbrücken ===

Jan 2019 – May 2019

Machine Learning Researcher

- Achievement: Mathematically solved optimal decision-making problem under strategic behaviour using real & synthetic credit card data.
- Duties: Guiding the project, Working closely with cross-functional teams, Designing data-driven solutions.
- Research Areas: Fairness, Optimal Decision-Making, Machine Teaching

#### statNLP @ SUTD-MIT

Machine Learning Intern

LSIR @ EPFL

Singapore \_\_\_\_

Jul 2016 – Oct 2016

- Achievement: Developed a novel approach for an efficient low-dimensional network embedding.
- Duties: Managing research project, Using new and creative techniques to modify previous solutions.
- Research Areas: Network Embedding, Graph Representation Learning

Duties. Wallaging research project, osing new and creative techniques to modify previous solution

Information Systems Research Intern

Lausanne 📩

Jan 2016 – May 2016

Hong Kong **S** 

Jul 2015 - Oct 2015

- Achievement: Significantly modified the accuracy of several state-of-the-art deep learning algorithms in word embedding.
- Duties: Developing scalable machine learning techniques to drive business outcomes for a giant food-industry stakeholder.
- Research Areas: Convex Optimization, Natural Language Processing, Word Embedding

Machine Learning Intern

- Achievement: Introduced a novel measure for mean first traverse distance on complex networks.
- Duties: Supporting the team in mathematical solutions.
- Research Areas: Network Science, Graph Representation Learning

# **Graduate Teaching Experience**

#### Monash University

SyMLab @ HKUST

Head TA for Multi agent systems and collective behaviour

Semester 2 - 2022

 Duties: Supervising a team of 4 graduate teaching assistants, Liaising with course coordinators, Advising 40 graduate students, Preparing course and exam materials, Organizing teaching resources.

TA for Computational Modelling and Simulation

Semester 1 - 2020 & 2021

## **Technical skills**

- Dynamically-typed Programming: Python, MATLAB, R
- o Data Visualization: Wolfram Alpha, Tableau, MuxViz, Gephi
- Symbolic Programming: Mathematica
- Markup Programming: △TEX, HTML

# **Presentations and Speeches**

- Oct 2022: University of Oxford
- Oct 2022: University College London (UCL)
- July 2022: Spotlight at ICML
- o July 2021: Workshop on Socially Responsible Machine Learning ICML
- July 2020: Machine Learning Summer School (MLSS)
- o Dec 2019: Human-Centric Machine Learning (HCML) Workshop NeurIPS

# **Honors and Awards**

- o LĢG Top 20 reviewers award, Learning on Graphs (LoG) Conference 2022.
- Travel award, ICML 2022, Baltimore, United States.
- o Among 16 electess globally to **NETHIKE 2022** Summer School by **ETH** Zürich, Switzerland.
- Among 30 electees globally to Complex networks: theory, methods, and apps Spring School, Italy.
- Travel award, NetSci-X 2022, Porto, Portugal.
- $\circ$  **E** Accepted to **Machine Learning Summer School (MLSS 2020)**, Germany: acceptance rate of 13.8%.
- Travel award, NeurlPS 2019, Vancouver, Canada.
- Ranked among top **0.05%** in the Iranian nation-wide university entrance exam of Maths and Physics.

### **Publications**

A full list of my publications is on my Google Scholar. My 5 recent publications in flagship Al conferences/journals:

- M. Khajehnejad, F. Habibollahi, R. Nock, E. Arabzadeh, P. Dayan, and A. Dezfouli, "Neural Network Poisson Models for Behavioural and Neural Spike Train Data". In Proc. of the 39th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML 2022), Spotlight paper.[link] (Acceptance Rate = 21.9%)
- A. Khajehnejad, M. Khajehnejad, M. Babaei, K. P. Gummadi, A. Weller, B. Mirzasoleiman "CrossWalk: Fairness-enhanced Node Representation Learning". In Proc. of the AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence 2022, (AAAI-22).[link] (Acceptance Rate = 15%)
- M. Khajehnejad, A. A. Rezaei, M. Babaei, J. Hoffmann, M. Jalili, A. Weller "Adversarial Graph Embeddings for Fair Influence Maximization over Social Networks". In Proc. of the 29th International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence 2020 (IJCAI'20).[link] (Acceptance Rate = 12.6%)
- M. Khajehnejad, S. Tsirtsis, B. Tabibian, A. Singla, B. Schölkopf, M. Gomez-Rodriguez "Optimal Decision Making Under Strategic Behavior". In Proc. of the 33rd Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS 2019: Human-Centric Machine Learning workshop).[link]
- M. Khajehnejad, F. Habibollahi, A. Gaurav, B. J. Kagan, "Biological Neurons vs Deep Reinforcement Learning: Sample efficiency in a simulated game-world". In Proc. of the 36th Conference on Neural Information Processing Systems (NeurIPS 2022: DeepRL, MemARI, and LMRL) and accepted in the journal of Nature Machine Intelligence. [link]